Furth, Josef Herbert; Papers ger036
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Typescripts and published versions of essays, speeches and position papers, 1932-1981; 5; 181 folders
  - Reviews by Furth of works by others, 5.152
    - Hunold, Albert.Volksbeschäftigung, Inflation und Planwirtschaft, 1952 August (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 16)
    - Economic Survey of Europe in 1950. Economic Survey of Europe in 1951, 1952 September (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 17)
    - Niehans, Jürg.Ausgleichsgesetze der Amerikanischen Zahlungsbilanz, 1953 June (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 18)
    - Mendershausen, Horst.Two Postwar Recoveries of the German Economy, 1955; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 19)
    - Papers and Proceedings of the First International Credit Conference. Vol. IV, 1955 August (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 20)
    - Zijlstra, J.De Omloopssnelheid van het Geld en zijn Betekenis voor Geldwaarde en Monetair Evenwicht, 1956; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 21)
    - Grenander, U. and M. Rosenblatt.Statistical Analysis of Stationary Time Series, 1957; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 22)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar.An International Economy. Problems and Prospects, 1957; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 23)
    - Kessler, G. A.Monetair Evenwicht en Betalingsbalansevenwicht, 1959; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 24)
    - Chandler, Lester V.The Economics of Money and Banking, 1960; typescript, reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 25)
    - Fritsch, Bruno.Geschichte und Theorie der amerikanischen Stabilisierungspolitik 1933-1939 / 1946-1953, 1960; typescript, reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 26)
    - Jacobsson, J.Some Monetary Problems -- International and National, 1960; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 27)
    - Palyi, Melchior.Currencies at the Crossroads -- Lessons of the European Currency Experiments, 1960; typescript, reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 28)
    - Vernon, R.Trade Policy in Crisis, 1960; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 29)
    - Shannon, Ian.The Economic Functions of Gold, 1962; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 30)
    - James, Emile.Problèmes Monétaires d'Aujourd'hui, 1965 January 13 (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 31)
    - Graebner, W.Die Wirkungsgrenzen der amerikanischen Notenbankpolitik, 1968; reprint (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 32)
    - "Comments on Treasury Paper on Exemption of Export Credits from Federal Reserve Voluntary Foreign Credit Restraint Programs", 1968 September 12; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 33)
    - Eagly, Robert V. (ed.).The Swedish Bullionist Controversy, 1971; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 34)
    - "Comments on draft on the Problem of the US Dollar" (Elrod), 1973 April 25; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 35)
    - "The International Monetary Fund, 1945-1965. Twenty Years of International Cooperation", 1973 June; typescript (Box 5 (5-Typescripts and published versions of essays, spee), Folder 36)
- Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors, 6; 8 folders
  Included in this series are typescripts of essays by other economists, which were sent to Furth for critical analysis and comment.
  - Adams, F. Gerard / Helen B. Junz. "A Note on the Effect of the 1965-69 Boom in the United States on World Trade", 1970 September 25; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 37)
  - Duncombe, Bruce F. "Border Tax Adjustments and International Economic Advantage", ca. 1970; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 38)
  - Machlup, Fritz. "Austrian Economics", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 39)
  - Machlup, Fritz. "Hayek, Friedrich August", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 40)
  - Marget, Arthur W. "Liszt und Parsifal", Undated; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 41)
  - Pauley, Bruce F. "Varieties of Austrian Anti-Semitism: From Empire to Republic". Speech text, 1979 May 25-1979 May 26 (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 42)
  - Robertson, J. L. "Remarks before the Independent Bankers Association of America". Speech text, 1972 March 15 (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 43)
  - Young, Ralph A. "Supplementary Note on Open Market Transactions in Foreign Exchange", 1962 April 13; typescript (Box 5 (6-Typescripts of essays, papers by other authors), Folder 44)
- Course and lecture notes, 1942-1974; 7; 29 folders
  This series contains lecture outlines, course notes, grading sheets and other course materials for courses taught by Furth at Lincoln University in Pennsylvania, The Catholic University and The American University in Washington, D.C., The Johns Hopkins University in Maryland and the Foreign Service Institute in Washington.
  - Economic Policy I, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 45)
  - Elementary Economics, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 46)
  - Elementary Economics II, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 47)
  - International Economics, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 48)
  - Labor Economics, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 49)
  - Government and Business, 1942-1943 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 50)
  - International Economic Policy, 1946-1947 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 51)
  - Economic Theory, 1946-1947 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 52)
  - History of Economic Thought. Catholic University, 1946-1950 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 53)
  - Mathematical Economics, 1947-1948 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 54)
  - European Recovery Problems, 1949-1950 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 55)
  - Theory of Economic (Business) Fluctuations. The American University, 1948-1961 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 56)
  - The International Monetary Order and the United States. Université Internationale de Sciences Comparées, Luxembourg, 1960 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 57)
  - Economic Growth and Development. The American University, 1951-1966 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 58)
  - Monetary Policy. Georgetown University, Spring 1960 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 59)
  - International Finance. Foreign Service Institute, 1966-1968 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 60)
  - International Finance. International Banking Seminar, 1967 April (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 61)
  - Introduction to International Economics, Summer 1968 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 62)
  - International Economics: Macro. School of Advanced International Studies, The Johns Hopkins University, 1968-1969 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 63)
  - Introduction to International Economics. University of Michigan, Summer 1968; Summer 1969 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 64)
  - Foreign Affairs Management Seminars, 1968-1969 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 65)
  - International Payments System. Foreign Service Institute, 1969-1971 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 66)
  - Senior Seminar in Foreign Policy. Foreign Service Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 67)
  - Introduction to International Economics. Foreign Service Institute, Summer 1969; Summer 1972 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 68)
  - Introduction to International Economics. Foreign Service Institute, Summer 1973 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 69)
  - International Economics II, 1971-1972 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 70)
  - The American Economy. Foreign Service Institute, 1969-1972 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 71)
  - History of Economic Thought. Foreign Service Institute, 1969-1974 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 72)
  - Trade Expansion Seminars. Foreign Service Institute, 1972-1975 (Box 5 (7-Course and lecture notes), Folder 73)